Lukas Müller

Full Stack Developer

✓ fat.manfm1111@gmail.com

S live:.cid.fe5545651a1ef5f7

1995/07/19

Oprtmund, Germany

https://github.com/GreenCat1996



I am a seasoned full-stack software engineer with nearly 10 years of experience in web development, most recently with a successful eCommerce startup.

I specialize in Next.js, React, and React Native web, mobile, and TV apps.

I have also worked with major global media companies on APIs and database integrations for SaaS applications.

LANGUAGES

English Germany

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Marine Science, University of Southampton

2013 – 2016 Southampton, UK

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, GraphQL, SQL

Tools

Git, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Slack, Figma, Adobe Illustrator

Frameworks

Next.js, React Native, NestJS, Tailwind CSS, Jest, MUI (Material UI)

Paradigms

Web Architecture, Management

Libraries/APIs

React, REST APIs, Node.js

Platforms

MacOS, Visual Studio Code (VS Code), Netlify, Firebase, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Storage

MongoDB

Other

App UI, Websites, Front-end, Web Development, APIs, Storybook, User Interface (UI), eCommerce, Front-end Architecture, Architecture, Lottie, Strapi, React Query, Plugins

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Qogita

2021/01 - 2023/06

- Increased customer engagement and sign-up in US markets as part of a small team dedicated to business growth.
- Contributed to the design system of components used across web products and published packages of shareable assets and types as GitHub npm packages.
- Maintained and updated a Next.js website, the primary entry point for global buyers on a major eCommerce platform.

• Worked on an Agile team releasing regular, iterative updates to the website using TDD principles and engaging in code reviews for other developers.

Web Developer, FX Digital

2016/11 - 2020/12

- Led a team on a high-profile, tight-deadline project for the Royal Shakespeare Company for a virtual theater performance streamed during the pandemic.
- Created an admin panel and associated design system in React and Storybook to be used by clients and the internal admin.
- Contributed to developing a SaaS video streaming back end built using microservices and an event stream database.
- Led a small team of developers focused on producing a video streaming connected TV app to use as a demo tool for international trade shows.

PROJECTS

Website and Customised CMS for a High-end Real Astate Agency ☑

A Next.js website designed and built with Tailwind CSS and React-query for a super-prime property agency based in London, deployed to Netlify. The front end pulls data from a CMS I created using Strapi, connected to a Postgres DB hosted at Railway. The client's data is stored on a property CRM, so I built a custom Strapi plug-in to enable manual data syncing between their CRM and the website back end to avoid the API charges imposed by their 3rd-party CRM. Integrated with the Google Maps API to display custom-styled maps for each property.

eCommerce Site for Global Startup 🗷

I was one of the leading front-end developers on a global, high-investment eCommerce website built using Next.js and TypeScript on the front end and integrating with REST APIs on a Python back end. I was in charge of implementing new features, reviewing code from other developers, contributing to architectural decisions, and regular maintenance and improvement of the codebase.

Website for an International Finance Company ☑

A static brochure site for a large multinational medical communications company. I was the sole developer working from a set of PDFs with a deadline of just four weeks. I used strong imagery and subtle interactive elements to lead the visitor through the site and highlight key factors about the business.

Online Ticketing Website and Livestreaming Portal for the Royal Shakespeare Company ☑

A two-part website built for the Royal Shakespeare Company to drive ticket sales and provide an entry point for their first interactive virtual performance of A Midsummer Night's Dream. Finished during the pandemic to a tight deadline, this was a visually stunning body of work that comprised a ticketing and information website and a separate virtual "lobby" website. Interactive "fireflies" and animated backgrounds were created using Lottie files, adding a unique feel to the site.

I led a team of three developers driving the ticketing site with a major focus on accessibility, incorporating features like high contrast mode and image and animation removal for visually impaired users.

Online Presence for a Small Retail Business

A Next.js site built for a small local business using WordPress as a headless CMS to allow the client to handle content updates easily. I designed and built the site using a combination of WordPress and ACF to generate data from the WordPress API to be consumed by the front end built using Next.js, Tailwind CSS, and React Query.